Miguel Espinoza

Backend Developer at Apsis International AB

purefan@outlook.com

Experience

Backend Developer at Apsis ProspectEye AB

September 2014 - Present (1 year 5 months)

Development, optimization and maintenance of backend infrastructure - Refactor database queries - Develop "tags" for ProspectEye's "Follow Up" feature. - Develop server side components. - Monitor database operations. - Implement new servers into the cluster. - Respond to database replication incidents. - Respond to security incidents. - Write Unit tests for several modules. - Fix errors reported by New Relic. - Implement iptable rules to isolate servers - Monitor tcp dumps with Wireshark - Train support staff - Assist sales personnel

Lead Web Developer at Benc Enterprises AB

July 2010 - July 2014 (4 years 1 month)

Ever since working for Benc Enterprises I've had many different roles, for example I've had to: - Design new features (planning and coding). - Design database tables and queries. - Design servers cluster for massive deployment (NodeJS, HA Mongodb, Redis). - Benchmark the product. - Benchmark web servers (namely NginX vs Apache in the context of our product). - Answer support tickets. - Have direct contact with clients/staff to coordinate specific situations (special situations outside support). - Troubleshoot clients' servers (outside of support). - Write automated tests (used Selenium Web Driver). - Fix bugs in the product. - Coordinate managers in other departments (not "with"). - Contact security testing companies. - Set up HAProxy in a Raspberry Pi (this was fun). - Stay up to date with technology to advise on new implementations. - Write articles for clients and developers. - Work remotely at times and set my own goals

CEO at Chess Heroes

January 2012 - May 2013 (1 year 5 months)

- Coordinate the marketing efforts - Develop all the components of the system - Develop the infrastructure - Arrange partnerships

Web developer at Phpfox

January 2009 - July 2010 (1 year 7 months)

- Develop new features (which involves researching of user experience, usability, performance, new technologies...) - Keep contact with clients to effectively troubleshoot issues. - Run benchmarks of different servers and configurations to measure the impact of different alternatives for in-house company projects. - Work closely with big clients to advise on technologies and how to best implement specific requirements. - Fix bugs in the product - Answer support tickets.

Support Technician at Benc Enterprises

January 2006 - January 2009 (3 years 1 month)

As a support technician I gained experience in the daily operations of our clients' business and more specifically I did: - Answer and stayed active in the forums. - Answer support tickets. - Write articles for clients and developers. - Debug code in client's servers. - Troubleshoot client's servers (outside of support)

Skills & Expertise

Information Security

PHP

MySQL

Web Development

HTML 5

jQuery

Apache

Java

Software Development

HTML

CSS

SQL

Node.js

Nginx

MVC

XHTML

Databases

JavaScript

AJAX

Subversion

Git

LAMP

Bash

Open Source

Linux

C++

XML

Web Applications

Facebook API

Android

HTML5

Programming

Visual Studio

Eclipse

phpMyAdmin

Web Services

Joomla

Python

Front-end

.NET

CMS

Microsoft SQL Server

UML

WordPress

Mobile Applications

Summary

Through my many years in the web development industry I have had the chance to work with many types of clients, from individuals who need a small fix in their personal websites to companies implementing systems used by millions. Having served projects as a database administrator, programmer, project manager, security analyst... has prepared to deal with stressful situations and deliver higher-than-expected results. Specialties: Web Development, Information Security, Training and Coaching

Courses

Lead Web Developer

Benc Enterprises AB MySQL DBA - 2008 - Mexico City

Education

Luleå University of Technology

Master's degree, Computer and Information Systems Security/Information Assurance, 2016

Universidad Interamericana de Costa Rica

Bachelor, Computer Information Systems, 2007 - 2009

Interests

Information Security, Chess, NginX, NodeJS, MySQL

Certifications

CompTIA Security ce

CompTIA August 2015 to August 2018

Languages

English

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

Spanish

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

Publications

iDate Berlin 2013 - The Future of Online Dating

Authors: Miguel Espinoza

Volunteer Experience

Developer at ActionAid

December 2015 - Present (2 months)

Along with a great team we tackled the challenge of gender inequality issue put forth by ActionAid, we focused on young girls between the ages of 8 and 12 and tried to give them access to important female figures. Our project is called JujuBe and we won the Best Gamification category at the Malmö http:// OpenHack.io challenge

Miguel Espinoza

Backend Developer at Apsis International AB

purefan@outlook.com



3 people have recommended Miguel

"Miguel is one of the most brilliant developers I have ever worked with. His deep knowledge of software architecture and his passion for writing robust and secure code makes him an extremely important part of the development team at Apsis. It has been a true pleasure working with him."

— **Kevin Ivan**, worked with Miguel at Apsis ProspectEye AB

"Miguel is a huge part of what has made phpFox the amazing social networking script that it is. From 2006-2010, myself and my staff had the opportunity to work with him countless times in going the extra mile for mutual clients in the fantastic partnership that Ubiquity enjoyed with phpFox. The entire time he's been incredibly committed and very easy to work with."

— Corey Northcutt, was with another company when working with Miguel at Benc Enterprises AB

"Miguel is punctual and a skilled developer. He's also very friendly, one of the nicest person I have ever had the honor to work with."

— Anna Eliasson, managed Miguel indirectly at Phpfox

Contact Miguel on LinkedIn